Now, let's look at the second metric which is Recall.
Recall is the answer to the following question.
Out of the points that are labeled positive,
how many of them were correctly predicted as positive?
So in the medical model, recall is the answer to the following question.
Out of the sick patients,
how many did we correctly diagnosed as sick?
So remember, precision was out of the patients who were diagnosed as sick,
how many were actually sick?
But recall is the opposite.
Out of the patients are sick,
how many did we correctly diagnosed as sick?
It can be seen as a reach of the algorithm.
How many of the positive points did I manage to catch?
The answer is calculated with this row.
And as we can see, this row catches a critical case labelled
by an X so we can see that recall is important in the medical model.
Now to calculate recall, we do the following.
From a 1200 sick patients,
how many did we diagnose correctly?
That's a thousand divided by 1200 which is 83.3%.
This model better have a high recall because we're trying to
correctly catch as many of the sick people as possible.
Now in the e-mail model,
recall is defined similarly.
It is calculated as follows.
From the spam emails,
how many of them did we correctly send to the spam folder?
The answer is in this row over here,
so we have a hundred correctly sent to the spam folder divided by 270 total spam emails.
It's a low number. It's 37%.
But remember, we are worried about avoiding this X over here.
Since we don't mind if we don't catch
all the spam emails as long as the ones we caught are spam.
So it's okay that this model has a low recall.
Now let's do a similar exercise as before.
In this linear model over here,
what is the recall?
Enter your answer below.