Now, we have learned precision and recall so as we've
seen our medical model has a precision of 55.7%,
and a recall of 83.3%.
It's supposed to be a hierarchical model.
Our spam detector has the precision of 76.9% and a recall of 37%,
and it's supposed to be a high-precision model.
Now the question is, do we want to be carrying two numbers around all the time?
Do we want to carry precision in one pocket and recall in the other one,
and always be looking at both,
any time we make a decision?
Well that's inconvenient, right?
We kind of want to only have one score.
So the question is, how do we combine these two scores into one?
Can we think of a way?
Well, a pretty simple way, is taking the average, right?
So let's take the average of precision and recall.
In the left, we get 69.5%,
in the right, we get 56.95%.
And that's an okay metric,
but I'm sure you're probably thinking in your head,
that's not very different than accuracy, right?
That's not saying too much.
And the way to see how this average is not the best idea,
is to try and in the extreme examples,
so the credit card fraud example.
So again, we have a bunch of good and fraudulent credit card transactions.
And let's pick a terrible model one,
which says, all transactions are good.
So what does the precision of this model?
Well the precision is, out of the ones we classified as bad,
how many of them are bad?
That's a questionable number, because we didn't label anything as fraudulent,
so it's kind of zero divided by zero which is undefined.
But it makes sense to think of it as 100%, right?
Since we made zero mistakes among the ones who predicted positive,
which is a precision tries to measure.
So let's say this model has a 100% precision.
Now, as for the recall, the recall is,
how many of the fraudulent transactions do we catch?
Well since we caught none,
this number is zero.
So the average between precision and recall is 50%,
since it's the average of a hundred and zero.
Now the question is, do I want to give this horrendous model of 50%?
It kind of seems like a really high score for such a lousy model.
I kind of want to give it a much lower score, perhaps even zero.
For average is not that good. Now, let's try the opposite.
Let's try the model that says that all transactions are fraudulent.
What is the precision of this model?
Well, out of all the transactions that are said are fraudulent,
472 were actually fraudulent.
So the precision is 472 divided by 284,807, which is 0.16%.
And the recall is actually pretty good,
because out of the 472 fraudulent transactions, I caught all of them.
So the recall is 472 divided by 472 which is 100%.
So again, the average of the two is the average of .16 on a hundred, which is 50.08.
Again, a very high score for a really lousy model.
So we want to give it a lower score,
maybe something close to zero.
So in summary, average is not the greatest thing in
principle if either precision or recall is very low.
We want the number to be low,
even if the other one is high.
So here's a solution.
There's another type of average called the harmonic mean,
and it works as follows.
Let's say we have two numbers X and Y. X is smaller than Y,
and we have the arithmetic mean over here.
That is the average X plus Y divided by two.
And we have something called the harmonic mean,
which is defined by two X Y divided by X plus Y.
And it's kind of an average two,
in the sense that if the two numbers are equal,
we get X or Y,
and it always lies between X and Y.
But actually, it's a mathematical fact that
the harmonic mean is always less than the arithmetic mean.
So it's kind of closer to the smaller number,
than to the higher number.
So it's a good example if the precision is one and the recall is zero.
The average is 0.5, but the harmonic mean is,
if you plug it in the formula, zero.
Another example, if the precision is 0.2 and the recall is 0.8,
then the arithmetic mean is 0.5,
but the harmonic mean is 0.32.
So it closer to the lower number.
So from now on, we will not be using the average or arithmetic mean,
but we will be using the harmonic mean.
And that's going to be called F1 score.
And as we said, the F1 score is closer to the smallest between precision and recall.
So if one of this particularly low,
the F1 score kind of raises a flag.
The average kind of says, if one is good,
but the other one is bad, then the average is okay.
But the F1 score,
raises the flag if one of them is small.
So we can now go back to the credit card fraud example and calculate the F1 score.
Since it's going to be the harmonic mean between the precision which is 100%,
and the recall which is zero.
We can plug in the formula,
and actually get an F1 score of zero.
This is much closer to what the models should score.
So, in the following two quizzes,
we'll let you calculate the F1 score of the medical model and the spam email model.