So, for the medical model, it seems that we'd much rather
misdiagnose a healthy person as sick and send them for more tests,
than misdiagnose a sick person who's healthy and send them home without treatment.
In this case, a false negative is much worse than a false positive.
So the rule of this model is,
I want to find all the sick people.
I'm okay if I accidentally bring some more as sick,
but I need to find all the sick people.
And for the spam email model, let's see.
A false negative means a spam email made its way into your inbox,
and all you have to do is delete it.
So it's a bit of an inconvenience.
On the other hand, what's a false positive?
Your grandma, the poor lady learned to type an email only to tell
you she baked cookies and you delete it. That's terrible.
So here, we want to punish false positives more than false negatives.
So this model basically says,
I don't really care if I find all the spam emails,
but one thing is for sure,
if I say that an email is spam, it better be spam.
So as we can see, the medical model and the email model are fundamentally different.
The medical model as we saw is okay with false positives,
but not with false negatives.
Since we're okay misdiagnosing some patients
as sick as long as we find all the sick people.
The email model on the other hand,
is okay with false negatives but not with false positives,
since we don't necessarily need to find all the spam emails.
But one thing is for sure,
that if we do label something as spam, it better be spam.
For this, we introduce use two metrics, precision and recall.
They will measure the exact things that we want namely,
the medical model needs to be a high-recall model,
and the email model needs to be a high-precision model.
We'll talk about them more in detail in the next couple of videos.