The implementation of random prediction in scikit-learn is pretty straightforward.
So, we just import the library here and then we declare it.
SparseRandomProjection is the faster.
So, there's a Gaussian random projection.
There's SparseRandomProjection.
This is a little bit more performant.
And then we fit.transform,
pass in our dataset, and then we get the new transformed dataset.
And so, here, if we want to declare or specify a specific value for epsilon,
we pass it here, or if we want to force it into a specific size or number of components.
If we don't specify anything,
the number of components is automatic and it's calculated
by using epsilon and by using the number of points or samples in the dataset,
so to choose based on the dataset.