Reinforcement learning problems can be solved using two broad categories of methods.
In Value-Based Methods like Monte-Carlo learning or Q-learning,
we try to represent the value of each state or state action pair.
Then, given any state we can pick the action with the best value.
This works well when you have a finite number of actions.
Policy-Based Methods on the other hand,
encode the mapping from states to actions without worrying about
value representations and then try to directly optimize the policy,
this is especially useful when you're action space is continuous,
or when you need stochastic policies.
The main challenge with policy-based methods is
that it is hard to compute how good a policy is.
This is where we bring in the idea of value functions back into the picture.
Instead of calculating the policy objective from rewards or returns,
what if we kept track of
state or state action values and use those to compute the objective?
That's exactly what Actor-Critic Methods are all about.