Recall the score function used in a typical policy gradients update rule.
For episodic tasks, where each instance has a clear beginning and end,
you can use the episode returns g t as the value of the score function.
It is equal to the discounted sum of
all rewards obtained in the remainder of the episode.
This forms the basis for Monte Carlo approaches,
such as the reinforce algorithm,
that performs updates at the end of each episode.
But what do you do if your task is not episodic?
If you do not have a clear termination point,
you won't be able to compute discounted returns.
Worse, when would you perform policy updates?
Clearly, we need a better score function.
Something that can be computed online as we interact with the environment.
Something that is not dependent on an entire episode being played out.
Let's replace the episode returns in
the update rule with the action value of the current state action pair.
Yes, the same action values we were trying to estimate in value-based methods.
We've come a full circle, haven't we?
Now where can we find these action values?
Unless we have an oracle to tell us exactly what these values should be,
we need to figure them out.
For instance, we can use
a temporal difference mechanism to iteratively update these action values.
Note that this process can run in parallel with
our policy updates and doesn't need an entire episode to be played out.
For this reason, it can be used with non episodic or continuing tasks.
In fact, you can pick any suitable representation to store
these Q values and an appropriate algorithm to update them.
Note that beta here is another learning rate or step size parameter,
just like alpha, but for value updates.