For most complex problems,
you will need to deal with continuous state and action spaces.
So, let's apply Q learning with function approximation to estimate the action values.
And here's a corresponding update rule for
the action value function expressed as a change in weights,
delta w. Note that theta and w are different parameter vectors,
but they are similar in the sense that they each approximate a function.
Theta characterizes the policy pi,
the probability of taking an action from a given state,
and w encodes the value Q hat of taking that action from that state.
Let's forget about the update rules and focus on the two functions.
Pi controls how your reinforcement learning agent behaves or acts.
Think of pi as a puppeteer controlling a puppet performing on stage.
And Q hat measures how good those actions are,
that is it critiques those actions.
These are your two function approximators.
Policy or actor, and value or critic.
You can design them separately,
perhaps using two neural nets,
and you can train them using separate processes as well.