Let's try to develop a complete architecture to train the actor and critic components.
Think about what the process looks like.
Initially, the actor follows some random policy and behaves pretty badly.
The critic observes this behavior and provides
feedback letting the actor know how bad it was.
Learning from this, the actor updates its policy pi and performs again,
and the critic continues to provide more feedback.
The critic also updates its own notes or
the value function so that it can provide better feedback.
This process can go on till the actor reaches
some predetermined threshold of performance,
or when not much improvement is seen.
Note that all along the critic has also been learning to give
better and better feedback by observing
the states and rewards obtained from the environment.
Now that we have a complete picture of how the different components interact,
let's reintroduce the math behind each component.
The policy approximator pi is parameterized by theta.
The value function approximator q hat is parameterized by w. At each time-step t,
we sample the current state of the environment as t. Using this as the input,
the policy produces an action At.
The actor takes this action in the environment producing
the next state St+1 as well as a reward Rt+1.
Now the critic computes the value of taking action A
in state St using the value function q hat,
and the actor updates its policy parameters theta using
this q value using these updated parameters the actor produces the next action At+1.
Finally, the critic updates its own value function.
This process is repeated at each time-step,
not just at the end of episodes.
So both the actor and the critic can make
more efficient use of the interactions with the environment.