So, how does the advantage function affect our actor-critic algorithm?
Let's start with our policy update rule.
We want to replace this state action value with the advantage value.
So, a natural approach is to define an additional state value function
V-hat parametrize by W-prime and subtract it from the Q value.
This means, the critic now has to keep track of two value functions,
Q-hat and V-hat, and learn them over time.
There is an easier way to do this.
It turns out that the TD error delta is a good estimator of the advantage function.
Using this method, the critic now has to compute and
learn a single value function V-hat. Neat, isn't it?