Actor-critic approaches are a variant of
policy-based methods that reuse the idea of value functions.
Remember, actor encodes the policy and critic encodes the value function,
tells the actor how good its policy is.
And since we can choose to represent the actor and critic separately,
we suddenly have a lot more flexibility in designing our reinforcement learning agents.
This has opened up a broad area of research where people are applying
reinforcement learning to problems that we could not even dream of solving before.
Deep mind surprise the world by beating humans at go,
but it also helped reduce Google's data center
cooling bill by 40 percent using reinforcement learning.
Open AI is probably more famous for Gym,
a platform that researchers can use to publish learning algorithms and
compare how they perform on different video games and simulated physics problems.
But they are also applying reinforcement learning to teach real physical robots
to learn complex tasks like picking and placing blocks and imitating humans.
Numerous other groups are actively pushing the boundaries
of what is possible to achieve using reinforcement learning,
and you can be a part of this community too.
But remember, to solve the next big challenge,
you need a healthy dose of creativity more than anything else.
Keep an eye on the latest advancements in the field.
Dive into research papers,
articles, and blog posts.
Try to implement new algorithms and experiment with them.
I'm really eager to see what problems you solve with reinforcement learning.