Deep-Q learning is an elegant algorithm that demonstrates how you
can use neural networks to solve reinforcement learning problems.
It has expanded the range of domains we can tackle,
especially those with large and continuous state spaces.
I'm sure you're eager to find out how it works,
that's exactly what we're going to do in this lesson.
We'll first take a look at how neural networks can be used to represent value functions.
Next, we'll adapt the two main classes of model free approaches,
Monte Carlo and Temporal-Difference Learning to work with this new representation.
Remember that Q-learning is a variant of TD learning,
so this will prepare you to understand and
implement the Deep Q-learning algorithm yourself.
Finally, you'll learn how to harness the power of
deep learning including Convolutional and Recurrent Neural
Nets to teach computer's tasks that seem almost
impossible to learn from scratch like playing video games.