Earlier in this lesson,
we detailed an algorithm to calculate the state value function corresponding to a policy.
Now, we'll adopt that algorithm to
instead return an estimate of the action-value function.
So let's recall exactly how one-step temporal difference works.
The agent interacts with the environment.
At time step zero,
it receives some state S_sub_zero.
Then, it uses the policy to pick an action.
Immediately afterwards, the agent receives a reward and next state.
At this point, the agent uses its experience to
update its estimate for the value of the state from time zero.
At the next point in time,
the agent chooses an action, again,
by consulting the policy,
then it receives a reward and next state.
Then, it uses that information to update the value of the state from time one.
Then, the process continues where the agent
always consults the same policy to pick an action,
receives a reward and next state,
and then updates the value function.
So the question is,
how might we adapt this process to instead return an estimate of the action values?
Well, instead of having an updated equation that relates the values of successive states,
what we'll instead need to do is have an update equation
that relates the values of successive state-action pairs.
Then, instead of updating the values after each state is received,
the agent will instead update the values after each action is chosen.
But that's the only difference,
and if the agent interacts with the environment for long enough,
it will have a pretty good estimate of the action-value function.
In the upcoming concepts,
you'll learn more about how to use this algorithm in the search for an optimal policy.