So far, we've discussed how we might design the algorithm for Monte Carlo control.
I mentioned in the last video that we
still have some work to do with the evaluation step.
Towards this end, we discussed an algorithm for keeping
a running estimate of the mean of a sequence of numbers.
Remember that this algorithm focused on one state action pair,
which was visited some number and times.
The algorithm looks at each visit in order and successively updates the mean new.
So this algorithm currently,
can only update the value function estimate corresponding to a single state action pair.
Our next step is to change it a bit,
so that it can maintain estimates of values for many state action pairs.
Then, we'll be able to plug in that algorithm as
a new and improved evaluation step. So here's what we'll do.
The agent begins by sampling an episode from the environment.
Then, for every time step we look at the corresponding state action pair.
If it's a first visit,
we calculate the corresponding return.
Then, in accordance with the algorithm we examined for keeping the running mean,
we then just update the corresponding estimate of the action value.
And so when we go to plug in this stuff into our algorithm for our Monte Carlo control,
we also have to be careful to also initialize the number
of times we've visited each pair and we're getting there.
Your blackjack playing agent will soon have
a method for improving its strategy after every game.