In this lesson, we'll look at two more clustering methods.
The first one is called Hierarchical Clustering,
and it results in a structure of clusters that gives us
a visual indication of how clusters relate to each other.
And then, we'll look at Density-based Clustering.
Specifically, we'll look at an algorithm called DBSCAN,
which stands for Density-based Spatial Clustering of Applications with Noise,
which is robust against datasets with noise,
and does not require us to specify a number of clusters.
Basically, it clusters points that are densely packed together,
and labels other points as noise.
And this is an algorithm that works really well on the two-crescent dataset.
So, let's start by looking at hierarchical clustering in the next video.