So in the previous section we learned that we can
add to linear models to obtain a third model.
A a matter of fact we did even more.
We can take a linear combination of two models,
so the first model times a constant plus the second model times a constant plus a bias,
and that gives us a nonlinear model.
That looks a lot like perceptrons where we can take a value times a constant
plus another value times a constant plus a bias and get a new value.
And that's no coincidence.
That's actually the building block of neural networks.
So let's look at an example.
Let's say we have this linear model where the linear equation is 5x_1 - 2x_2 + 8.
That's represented by this perceptron.
And we have another linear model with equation 7x_1 - 3x_2 - 1,
which is represented by this perceptron over here.
Let's draw them nicely in here.
And let's use another perceptron to combine these two models using
the linear equation seven times
the first model plus five times the second model minus six.
And now the magic happens when we join these together and we get a neural network.
We clean it up a bit and we obtained this. All the weights are there.
The weights on the left tell us what equations the linear models have and the weights on
the right tell us what the linear combination is of
the two models to obtain the curved nonlinear model in the right.
So whenever you see a neural network like the one on the left,
think of what could be the nonlinear boundary defined by the neural network.
Now note that this was drawn using the notation that puts the bias inside the node.
These can also be drawn using the notation that keeps the bias as a separate node.
Here what we do is, in every layer we have
a bias unit coming from a node with a one on it.
So for example, the -8 on the top node
becomes an edge labelled -8 coming from the bias node.
We can see that this neural network uses
the sigmoid activation function on the perceptrons.