So our goal is to train our neural network.
In order to do this we have to define the error function.
So let's look again at what the error function was for perceptrons.
So here's our perceptiron.
In the left we have our input vector with entries x_1 up to x_n and one for
the bias unit and the edges with weights W_1 up to W_n and b for the bias unit.
Finally, we can see that this perceptron uses a sigmoid function.
And the prediction is defined as y_hat equals sigmoid of Wx+b.
And as we saw this function gives us the measure of
the error of how badly each point is being classified.
Roughly, this is a very small number if the point is correctly
classified and a measure of how far the point
is from the line if the point is incorrectly classified.
So what are we going to do to define the error function in a multilayer perceptron?
Well, as we saw, our prediction is simply a combination of matrix multiplications and
sigmoid functions but the error function can be the exact same thing, right?
It can be the exact same formula except now
y_hat is just a bit more complicated, and still,
this function will tell us how badly a point gets
misclassified except now it's looking at a more complicated boundary.