So here's a summary of what we do in machine learning.
First, we train a bunch of models with our training data.
Then, we use a cross-validation data to pick the best of these models.
And finally, we test it with the testing data to make sure our model is good.
So here's an example of training a logistic regression model.
Let's say, we have four candidates,
we train a model of degree one,
which is a line and one of degree two, three, and four.
We train them with the training data to find
the slope and the coefficients of the polynomials et cetera.
Then we use the cross-validation data to calculate say the F1 score of all these models.
And then, we pick the model with the highest F1 score.
As a final step, we use our testing data to make sure our model is good.
So the parameters of the algorithm in this case are the coefficients
of the polynomial but the degree of the polynomial is like a matter parameter.
We call those hyper parameters.
Let's see another example. Let's say,
we're training a decision tree.
So what are the hyper parameters?
Well, one of them is depth. Let's say we have one of depth one,
two, three, and four.
We use the training data to train a bunch of trees of depth one,
So the parameters here are the thresholds in the leaves and the nodes et cetera.
Then, we take the F1 score and calculate it on
the cross-validation set on each of these models.
Then we pick the one that did the best.
And finally, with the testing set,
we make sure this model is good.
So what happens if we have more than one hyper parameter?
Here we only have one which is depth.
What if we're training a support vector machine?
So in an SVM, we as we have some hyper parameters like
the kernel which can be linear or polynomial, for example.
And we also have the gamma parameter,
which if it's small, gives a solutions like this.
And if it's large,
It gives a solution like that.
So how do we pick the best combination between kernel and gamma?
Well, very simple, it's called grid search and it literally just says
make a table with all the possibilities and pick the best one.
Our columns here are the different kernels we can use, linear and polynomial.
And the rows are the different values of gamma.
It's recommended to take a few values that grow exponentially such as 0.1,
1, 10, 100, 1000, etc.
So again, we use our training set to train a bunch of
linear models and polynomial models with different values of gamma.
Then we use the cross validation set to calculate the F1 score on all these models.
And then we simply pick the one with the highest F1 score.
And finally, we use a testing set to make sure that what we did was good.