So, to summarize, this is how I see machine learning.
We have a problem to solve,
which is represented by this broken car over here,
and we have some tools to fix it,
which are the algorithms of machine learning.
And finally, we have some measurement tools,
which we then use to measure each tool's performance.
Then, you pick the best tool to fix your car.
To be more specific in machine learning,
you have a problem which is some data you need to classify.
You also have a bunch of algorithms.
Things like neural networks, logistic regression,
polynomial regression, SVMs, decision trees,
random forests, et cetera.
And we have a bunch of metrics.
Things like model complexity graphs,
accuracy precision recall F1 score,
learning curves, et cetera.
And what you do, is you use these ones to test your models,
see how they're doing.
Pick the best one and that's what you use to model your data.
Then, when you have a new point, you can predict as label based on that model.
And that's it. That's how you test,
evaluate, and validate models.