And now we finally have the tools to write the pseudocode for
the Gradient Descent Algorithm and it goes like this.
Step one.
Start with random weights w_1 up to w_n and b,
which will give us a line- and not just a line,
but the whole probability function given by sigmoid of Wx+b.
Now for every point, we'll calculate the error and as we can see the error
is light from it's classified points and small for correctly classified points.
Now, for every point with coordinates x_1 up to x_n,
we update w_i by adding the learning rate
alpha times the partial derivative of the error function with respect to w_i.
We also update b by adding Alpha times
the partial derivative of the error function with respect to b.
This give us new weights w_i prime and then new bias b prime.
Now we've already calculated these partial derivatives and we know that the are
y^-y times x_i for
the derivative respect to w_i and y^-y for the derivative respect to b.
So that's how we'll update the weights.
Now repeat this process until the error is small,
or we can repeat it a fixed number of times.
The number of times is called the epoch and we'll learn them later.
Now this looks familiar.
Have we something like that before?
Well, we look at the points and what each point is doing is
it's adding a multiple of itself into the weights of
the line in order to get the line to move closer towards it if it's misclassified.
That's pretty much what the perception algorithm was doing.
So, in the next video we'll look at
the similarities because it's a bit suspicious how similar they are.