So first let's add some math.
We're going to label the horizontal axis corresponding to the test by
the variable X1 and the vertical axis corresponding to the grades by the variable X2.
So, this boundary line that separates the blue
and the red points is going to have a linear equation.
The one drawn has equation 2X1 + X2 - 18 = 0.
What does this mean?
This means that our method for accepting or rejecting students
simply says the following: Take this equation as our score,
the score is 2*Test + Grades - 18.
And when the student comes in, we check their score.
If their score is a positive number,
then we accept the student and if the score is a negative number,
then we reject the student.
This is called a prediction.
We can say by convention that if the score is zero we'll accept a student,
although this won't matter much at the end.
And that's it. That linear equation is our model.
In the more general case our boundary
will be an equation of the form W1X1 + W2X2 + b = 0.
We'll abbreviate this equation in vector notation of Wx + b = 0,
where W is the vector W1W2 and X is the vector X1X2.
And we simply take the product of the two vectors.
We refer to x as the input,
the W as the weights,
and the b as the bias.
Now for a student cooordinates X1X2 will denote a label as y,
and the label is what we're trying to predict.
So if the student gets accepted- namely the point is blue,
then the label is y = 1.
And if the student gets rejected- namely the point is red,
and the label is y = 0.
Thus, each point is in the form X1X2
y or y is one for the blue points and zero for the red points.
And finally, our prediction is going to be called ŷ and it
will be what the algorithm predicts that the label will be.
In this case ŷ is one if the algorithm predicts that the student
gets accepted- which means the point lies over the line,
and ŷ is zero if the algorithm predicts that the student
get rejected- which means the point is under the line.
In math terms, this means that the prediction ŷ is 1 if
Wx + b is greater than or equal to zero and 0 if Wx + b is less than zero.
So to summarize, the points above the line have ŷ
equals one and the points below the line have ŷ
equals zero and the blue points have y equals one and the red points have y equals zero.
And the goal of the algorithm is to have ŷ resembling
y as closely as possible- which is exactly
equivalent to finding the boundary line that keeps most of
the blue points above it and most of the red points below it.