So let's recap.
We have our data which is all the students.
The blue ones have been accepted and the red ones have been rejected.
And we have our model which consists of the equation,
2*Test + Grades -18 which gives
rise to this boundary line which is
the points where the score is zero and the prediction.
The prediction says that the student gets accepted if the score is positive or zero,
and rejected if the score is negative.
So now, we'll introduce the notion of a perceptron which is the building block of
neural networks and it's just an encoding of our equation into a small graph.
The way we build that is the following.
Here, we have our data and our boundary line and we fit it inside a node.
And now we have small nodes for the inputs which in
this case they are the test and the grades.
Here, we can see an example where Test = 7 and Grades = 6.
And what the perception does is it plots the points seven,
six and checks if the point is in the positive or negative area.
If the point's in the positive area then the returns a yes.
And if it is in the negative area, it returns a no.
So let's recall that our equation is Score = 2*Test + 1*Grade -18.
And that our prediction consists of accepting
the student if the score is positive or zero,
and rejecting them if the score is negative.
These weights 2, 1 and -18 are what define the linear equation.
And so, we'll use them as labels in the graph.
The two and one will label the edge is coming from X1, X2 respectively.
And the bias unit -18 will label a node.
Thus, when we see a node with these labels,
we can think of the linear equation they generate.
Another way to grab this node is to consider the bias as part of the input.
Now, this is W1 gets multiplied by X1 and W2 by X2.
It's natural to think that B gets multiplied by a one.
So we'll have the B labeling an edge is coming from a one.
Then what the node does is it multiply the values coming from
the incoming nodes by the values and the corresponding edges.
In this case, that's a 7*1,
a 6*2, and a 1* -18.
Then it adds them and finally,
it checks if the result is greater than or equal to zero.
If it is, then the node returns a yes, or a value of one.
And if it isn't, then the node returns is a no or a value of zero.
In this case, since the equation returns a one and that is greater than
zero then this node would return a value of one signaling that the student gets accepted.
We'll be using both notations throughout this class.
Although, the second one will be used more often.
In the general case,
this is how the nodes look.
We will have our node over here.
Then n inputs coming in with values X1 up to Xn,
and one and edges with weights W1 up to Wn and B,
corresponding to the bias unit.
And then the node calculates the linear equation Wx + b which is a summation from
I = 1 to n of WiXi +b.
This node then checks if the value is zero or bigger.
And if it is, then the node returns a value of one for yes.
And if not, then it returns a value of zero for no.
Note that we're using an implicit function here which is called, "The step function."
What the step function does,
is that it returns a one if the input is positive or zero,
and a zero if the input is negative.
So, in reality, these perceptrons can be seen as a combination of
nodes where the first node calculates the linear equation and the inputs on the weights.
And the second node applies the step function to the result.
These can be graphed as follows,
the summation sign represents a linear function in the first node,
and the drawing represents a step function in the second node.
In the future, we'll use different step functions
so this is why it's useful to specify it in the node.
So as we've seen, there are two ways to represent perceptrons.
The one on the left has a bias unit coming from an input node with a value of one,
and the one in the right has the bias inside the node.