Policy gradients have proven to be
a very powerful family of methods and reinforcement learning.
As we've seen in this lesson,
they have several advantages over value based methods.
They directly map from states to actions,
so you don't need to deal with value functions.
You can use them to learn continuous control tasks where your actions are real numbers.
Not just discrete choices.
And they represent the choice over actions as a probability distribution,
so you get true stochastic policies for free.
Several improvements to the basic policy gradients approach
have been proposed and new ones are coming out all the time.
This is an active area of research.
If you want to keep up with the latest advancements,
look for recently published papers in this area,
try to understand the algorithms,
and implement them yourself.