Here is the outline for this section.
In machine learning, we have a problem to solve.
Normally, the problem corresponds to evaluating some data and making predictions.
The problem is represented by this broken car over here.
Now, in order to solve it,
we have a few tools.
These tools are the algorithms,
things like linear or logistic regression, SVM's,
neural networks, decision trees, etc.
How do we know which tool works best?
Well, for that we have a bunch of measurement tools
and we use them to evaluate all the algorithms.
Once we evaluate the algorithms and
their parameters and decide which ones are best for a problem,
then, we go ahead and solve our problem.
In this section, we learn
the measurement tools so we'll learn a bunch of metrics and techniques that will
tell us when an algorithm is working well with
the data and how to tweak them to work best for us.