Here, you see the natural evolution of a melanoma over the years from 2003 to 2006.
And there's characteristics that doctors use for finding melanomas.
They look at the fuzziness of the border, the asymmetry,
the coloration, of course,
the growth rate if it is accessible.
But still, classifying melanomas, as I've shown you,
is very hard problem.
Partially, it's hard because some people have lots of moles.
These are clinical images of two backs and you can see how many moles they are,
and finding the one that's malignant is really, really hard.
So, dermatologists are extremely highly trained to find melanomas and carcinomas.
And as a result, they make a lot of money.
The average dermatologist in United States makes more than $400,000 a year.
There is about 10,000 of them in total and they are incredibly hard to train
because they need to make life and death decisions in diagnosing your skin.