Just to show how difficult it is to find skin cancer,
I challenge you to look at this image,
and if you have a doctor in your family or your friends,
show them the image and ask them what they think is cancer.
You can see different types of lesions,
and you can see benign and malignant lesions,
and these are all correctly classified.
And I challenge you to find the pattern that tells
the 12 images on the top part from the 12 images at the bottom. It's not an easy thing.
That's how you thought a neural network is a good candidate because neural networks can
process hundreds of thousands of images as
a human doctor can never study as many as you can feed into a neural network.