And now, on to apply the Naive Bayes algorithm.
We want to calculate the probability that an email is
spam given that it contains the word easy and money.
And as we briefly stated before, we'll make an assumption.
We'll assume that the product of
the probabilities that the email is spam if it contains the word
easy times the probability that it's spam if it contains
the money is the desired probability.
This is a naive assumption because it could be that these two are not independent.
Say, it could be that emails containing the word
easy are more likely to contain the word money,
but it turns out that this assumption ends up working really well in many situations.
So we'll make it. And so,
we obtain that the probability of the email being
spam is one-half times two-thirds which is one-third.
For clarity, I've written the actual formula for
these two calculations using Bayes Theorem that we've done previously.
And these two give us again 0.5 and 0.67 for the posteriors.
So finally, we multiply them and we'll obtain the probability of an email being
spam given that it has the words easy and money is 0.33.
And in general, this is what happens.
Let's say we have n suspicious words,
for example, easy, money, cheap, et cetera.
These are our conditions,
and when we get a new email,
we test against them.
So, we make the naive assumption that the probability of spam given
that the email contains all these words is the product of these probabilities.
And how do we calculate each one of them?
Easy, using Bayes Theorem.