Now, let's look at an interesting application of Bayes Theorem.
Let's say we're not feeling very well and we go to the doctor.
The doctor says, "There's a terrible disease going on,
I'll administer a test for you."
Moreover, she says that the test has 99 percent accuracy.
More specifically, she says that for every 100 patients that are sick,
the test correctly diagnoses ninety nine of them,
and for every 100 patients that are healthy,
the test correctly diagnosis 99 of them.
If you want to be technical, these are actually called sensitivity and specificity.
Then while we were waiting for our test,
we researched the internet and find that on average,
one of every 10,000 people suffer from the disease.
The next day, the doctor calls with terrible news.
She says that we have tested positive for the disease. So now we're panicking.
But before panicking, let's turn to math and actually
calculate what is the probability of being sick. So, here's a quiz.
Given the two pieces of information that the test has
99 percent accuracy and that one out of every 10,000 people have the disease,
what do you think the probability is that we're sick?
Is it from zero to 20 percent, from 20 to 40,
40 to 60, 60 to 80,
or 80 to 100?
Take your guess and enter it.