Now, the question is, "How do we use this wonderful base theorem to do machine learning?"
And the answer is, repeatedly.
Let's look at this example,
a spam email classifier.
So, let's say we have some data in the form of a bunch of emails.
Some of them are spam, and some of them are not spam, which we call ham.
Spam are, "win money now,
make cash easy, et cetera."
And the ham are "How are you?,
There you are, et cetera."
And now, what we'll do is,
when a new email comes in and say,
"Easy money," and we want to check if it's spam or ham.
So we take it word by word.
Of course, we can be more effective if we took into
account the order of the words but for this classifier, we won't.
It's surprising how good it can be even if it
doesn't take into account the order of the words.
So let's study the first word, say, easy.
We can see the word easy appears once among the three spam emails,
and once among the five ham emails.
And the word money, it appears twice among the three spam emails,
and ones among the five ham emails.
So let's start with calculating some preliminary probabilities as an exercise.
Given the data we have,
what is the probability of an email containing the word easy given that it is spam?
Here are some options.
And let's also calculate it for the other word.
Again, given our data,
what's the probability of an email being spam given that it contains the word money?
Here are the options, enter your answer below