So, let's see. We have
three spam emails and one of them contains the word "easy" which means
the probability of an email containing the word "easy" given that it's spam is one-third.
Since two out of the three spam emails contained the word "money," then the probability
of an email containing the word "money" given that it's spam is two-thirds.
And similarly, there are five ham emails and one of them contains the word "easy," then
the probability of an email containing the word "easy" given that it is ham is one-fifth.
And same thing for the word "money."
And the main gist of Bayesian learning is the following: We go
from what's known which is P of easy given spam,
and P of money given spam,
to what's inferred which is P of spam given that it contains the word
"easy" which is one half since there are
two emails containing the word "easy" and only one of them is spam,
and P of spam given that it contains the word "money" which is
two-thirds since there are three e-mails
containing the word "money" and two of them are spam.
And now, here's the naive part of my base.
We pretend that these are independent and just multiply them together to obtain
the probability that the email is spam if it
contains the word "easy" and the word "money."
Of course, this is not true in general.
But making this assumption normally gives us some pretty good results,
and it's not such a crazy assumption after all.
We'll see this more in detail later.