So now, we can calculate the weights of all our weak learners.
Let's remember that in the first one,
the sum of weights of the correctly classified points is seven,
and the sum of incorrect ones is three.
Therefore, the weight is natural logarithm of seven divided by three, which is 0.84.
For the second one, the sum of weights of the correctly classified points is 11,
and for the incorrect ones it's three.
So the weight is natural logarithm of 11 over three, which is 1.3.
And finally, for the third one,
the sum of correct weights is 19,
and for the incorrect ones it's three again.
So the weight is natural logarithm of 19 divided by three, or 1.84.
It sounds like the weights are increasing but don't get the wrong idea.
That only happens in this example.
In general, they will not necessarily be increasing.
So now, we have our three week learners with their corresponding weights of
0.84, 1.3, and 1.84.
And to combine them, basically,
we make them vote, except we weight the vote by the corresponding weight.
So for the positive area, we'll add the weight,
and for the negative area,
we'll subtract the weight. So let's do it.
We take the first model and add the positives and negatives of the weight to each region,
then we do the same thing with the second model,
and finally, with the third model.
And we calculate the sums which gives us these values.
And finally, when the value is positive,
then we say blue, and when it is negative, we say red.
And that's it. That's the combination of our weak learners.
And we can see how it forms a strong learner.
We can see that this model fits the data pretty well.
And that's it. That's AdaBoost.