Now let me show you a trick that will make a line go closer to a point.
Let's say we have our linear equation for example three x one plus four x two minus 10.
And that linear equation gives us a line which is
the points where the equation is zero and two regions.
The positive region drawn in blue with three x one plus four x two minus 10 is positive.
And the negative region drawn in red with
three x one plus four x two minus 10 is negative.
So, here we have our lonely misclassified point,
the point four coma five which is a red point in the blue area.
And the points has come closer.
So how do we get that point to come closer to the line?
Well the idea is we're going to take the four and the five,
and use them to modify the equation of the line
in order to get the line to move closer to the point.
So, here are parameters of the line three four and minus 10.
And the coordinates of the point are four and five.
And let's also add a one here for the bias unit.
So, what we'll do is subtract these numbers from
the parameters of the line to get three minus four,
four minus five and minus 10 minus one.
The new line will have parameters minus one,
minus one and minus 11.
And this line will move drastically towards the point.
Possibly even going over it and placing it in the correct area.
Now, since we have a lot of other points,
we don't want to make any drastic moves as you may
accidentally misclassify all our other points.
We want the line to make a small move towards the point,
and for this we need to take small steps towards the point.
So, here's where we introduce the learning rate?
The learning rate is a small number,
for example zero point one.
And what we'll do is instead of subtracting
four five and one from the coordinates of the line,
we'll multiply these numbers by zero point one,
and then subtract them from the equation of the line.
This means we'll be subtracting point four,
point five, and point one from the equation of the line.
Obtaining an equation of two point six
x one plus three point five x two minus 10 point one equals zero.
This new line will actually move closer to the point.
In the same way if we have a blue point in the red area,
for example the point one one,
it's positively labeled point in the negative area.
This point is also misclassified and it says come closer.
So, what do we do here is the same thing except now instead of
subtracting the coordinates to the parameters of the line, we add them.
Again, we multiply by the learning rate in order to make small steps.
So, here we take the coordinates of the point
one one and put an extra one for the constant term.
And now we multiply them by the learning rates zero point one.
Now, we add them to the parameters of the line.
And we get a new line with equation three point one
x one plus four point one x two minus nine point nine.
And magic. This line is closer to the point.
So, that's the trick we're going to use repeatedly for the perceptron algorithm.