Now, we finally have all the tools for describing the perceptron algorithm.
We start with a random equation which will determine some line and two regions,
the positive and the negative region.
Now we'll move this line around to get a better and better fit.
So we ask all the points how they're doing.
The four correctly classified points say, "I'm good."
And the two incorrectly classified points say, "Come closer."
So let's listen to the point in the right and
apply the trick to make the line closer to this point.
So here it is. Now this point is good.
Now let's listen to the point in the left.
The point says, "Come closer."
We apply the trick and now the line goes closer to it.
And it actually goes over it classifying correctly.
Now every point is correctly classified and happy.
So let's actually write the pseudocode for this perceptron algorithm.
We start with random weights,
W1 up to Wn and b.
This gives us the equation Wx + b,
the line and the positive and negative areas.
Now for every misclassified point with coordinates x1 up to xn we do the following.
If the prediction was 0, which means the point is a positive point in the negative area,
then we'll update the weights as follows.
For i = 1 to n, we change wi to wi + α × xi,
where α is the learning rate.
In this case, we're using 0.1.
Sometimes we use 0.01 etc. It depends.
Then we also change the bias unit to b + α.
That moves the line closer to the misclassified point.
Now if the prediction was one which means a point is a negative point in
the positive area then we'll update the weights in a similar way,
except we subtract instead of adding.
This means for i = 1,
change wi to wi minus alpha xi and change the bias unit b to be b - α.
And now the line moves closer to our misclassified point.
And now we just repeat the step until we get no errors or
until we have a number of errors that is small or simply we can just say,
do this step a thousand times and stop.
We'll see what are our options later in the class.