Now, you may be wondering what happens if we have more data columns,
so not just testing grades,
but maybe something else like the ranking of the student in the class.
How do we fit three columns of data?
Well, the only difference is that now we won't be working in two dimensions,
we'll be working in three.
So now we have three axis, X1 for the test,
X2 for the grades, and X3 for the class ranking.
And our data will look like this,
like a bunch of blue and red points flying around in 3D.
And our equation won't be aligned in two dimension but a plane in
three dimensions with a similar equation as before.
Now the equation would be W1X1 + W2X2 + W3X3 + B= 0,
which will separate the space into two regions.
This equation can still be abbreviated by WX + B = 0,
except our vectors will now have three entries instead of two.
And our prediction will still be Y high equals one if WX + B is
greater than or equal to zero and zero of WX + B is less than zero.
And what if we have many columns,
like say n of them?
Well, it's the same thing. Now our data just leaps in n dimensional space.
Now, I have trouble picturing things in more than three dimensions.
But if we can imagine that the points are just things with n coordinates called X1,
X2, X3, all the way up to Xn,
with our labels being y,
then our boundary is just an n-1 dimensional hyper-plane,
which is a high dimensional equivalent of a line in 2D or a plane in 3D.
And the equation of this n-1 dimensional hyper-plane is going to be
W1X1+ W2X2 + all the way to WnXn + B = 0,
which we can still abbreviate to WX + B = 0 where our vectors now have n entries.
And our prediction is still the same as before.
It is y hat equals 1 if WX + B is greater than or equal to
zero and Y hat equal zero if WX + B is less than zero.