Cluster validation is the procedure of evaluating
the results of a clustering objectively and quantitatively.
There are three categories of cluster validation indices.
The first are external indices.
And these are the scoring methods that we use if our data was originally labeled.
So, if we have a data set that is actually labelled,
we can use external indices to score how a clustering method did.
But most of the time,
the data that we have is not labelled specifically with unsupervised learning.
And so these are the cases where internal indices can be helpful
and these measure the fit between the data and structure using only the data.
The third category is relative indices,
and these indicate which of two clustering structures is better in some sense.
Basically, all internal indices can serve as relative indices.
Most validation indices are defined by compacting compactness and separability.
Compactness is basically a measure of how
close the elements of a cluster are to each other,
while separability is how far or distinct clusters are from each other.
The general assumption here is that
clustering methods are generally expected to produce clusters where
the elements of a cluster are the most similar to each
other and the clusters are the most distinct from each other.
If this sounds a bit too theoretical, that's okay.
We'll look at specific indices in the next videos.