So let's say we're studying the housing market,
and our task is to predict the price of a house given its size.
So we have a small house that costs $70,000 and a big house that costs $160,000.
We'd like to estimate the price of this medium-sized house over here.
So how do we do it?
Well, first we put them in a grid where the x-axis represents the size of
the house in square feet and the y-axis represents the price of the house.
And to help us out, we have collected some previous data in the form of these blue dots.
These are other houses that we've looked at and we've
recorded their prices with respect to their size.
In here, we can see that small house is priced at $70,000 and the big one at $160,000.
Now, it's time for a small quiz.
What do you think is the best estimate for the price of the medium house given this data?
Would it be $80,000,
$120,000, or $190,000?
Submit your answer.