So, this time there was a solution and the solution is B.
And here is the reason which is more subtle.
Our mean squared error,
is actually a quadratic function.
And quadratic functions have a minimum at the point in the middle.
Over here, we can see that the error for line A would be around here,
the error for line C would be around here,
and the one for line B would be somewhere around here.
So, we can see that the minimum mean square error is given by line B.
Here is a diagram of the errors,
and you can check with your eyes,
or even drawing a small example in calculating the areas.
That line B would be giving you the smallest mean square error.