So in the previous example,
we had a one column input and one column output.
The input was the size of the house and the output was the price.
So, we had a two-dimensional problem.
Our prediction for the price would be a line and
the equation would just be a constant times size plus another constant.
What if we had more columns in the input?
For example, size, and school quality.
Well now, we have a three-dimensional graph because we have
two dimensions for the input and one for the output.
So now, our points don't live in the plane,
but they look like points flying in three-dimensional space.
And what we do here is we fit a plane through them instead of fitting a line.
And our equation won't be a constant times one variable plus another constant.
It's going to be a constant times school quality,
plus another constant times size,
plus a third constant.
And that's what happens when we're in three dimensions.
So, what happens if we're in n dimensions?
So, in this case, we have n minus one columns in the input and one in the output.
So, for example, the inputs are size,
school quality, number of rooms, et cetera.
Well now, we have the same thing except our data lives in n-dimensional space.
So for our input, we have n minus one variables,
namely X1, X2, up to Xn minus one.
And for the output of the prediction,
we only have one variable, y hat.
And our prediction would be an n minus
one dimensional hyper plane living in n dimensions.
And since it's hard to picture n dimensions,
just think of a linear equation in n variables such as y hat equals W1X1 plus W2X2,
plus all the way to Wn minus one Xn minus one, plus Wn.
And that's how we do predictions for higher dimensions.
In order to find the weights W1 up to Wn,
the algorithm is exactly the same thing as for two variables.
We can either do the absolute or square tricks,
or we can calculate the mean absolute or square errors,
and minimize using grading descent.