So what happens if we have data that looks like this,
where a line won't really do a good job fitting it?
Maybe we would like to have a curve or some polynomial?
Maybe something along the lines of 2x cubed minus 8x squared, et cetera.
This can be solved using a very similar algorithm than linear regression.
All we have to do is, instead of considering lines,
we consider higher degree polynomials.
This would give us more ways to solve our problem.
For example, this problem here will make us solve for four weights,
w1, w2, w3 and w4.
But the algorithm is the same thing.
We just take the mean absolute or squared error and take the derivative the respect to
the four variables and use gradient descent to
modify these four weights in order to minimize the error.
This algorithm is known as polynomial regression.