So here's a trick that will help us fit a line through a set of points.
Let's say that these are points and we start by drawing some random line.
And we're going to ask every point what it
wants for the model to be better, and then listen to them.
So let's go one by one.
Let's take this point over here,
and ask it what would it want the line to do.
Well, the point would want the line to move closer.
So we'll listen to that point and move closer.
Now if we ask all the points,
they would tell us the same thing.
So we move closer to all of them,.
Then we listen to them again and we take another step that gets closer to all of them.
Now it's trickier because we have a point
underneath that pulls it down, but that's still okay.
And basically, the idea is that we take
a few steps that make us go closer to all the points.
And that's it, that's linear regression.
In the next few videos, we'll see this in a bit more detail.