So let's have a little refresher on how we move lines by changing the parameters.
So if we have a line of equation,
y = W1x + W2,
where W1 and W2 are constants,
it looks like this: W1 is the slope and W2 is the y-intercept,
which is where the line intersects the y-axis.
Now, what happens if we increase W1?
Well, we increase the slope so that means the line rotates like this.
If we decrease W1, then we're decreasing the slope so the line rotates like this.
Now, what happens if we increase the y-intercept W2?
Then, the line moves in a parallel way up like this.
If we decrease W2,
then the line moves like that to the bottom.
That's really all we're going to need for the tricks that are coming.