In the last video, we'll learn how to decrease
an error function by walking along the negative of its gradient.
Now in this video, we're going to learn formulas for these error functions.
The two most common error functions for a linear regression are
the mean absolute error and the mean squared error.
First, we'll learn the mean absolute error.
So, here's our point and our line.
The point has coordinates (x,
y) and the line is called y-hat since it's the prediction.
So, our prediction for this point is going to be the point in
the line with the same X coordinate as our point,
that is the point (x, y-hat).
This means the vertical distance from the point to the line is (y - y-hat),
and that's what we'll be calling the error.
Notice that this is not the actual distance to
the line since it would be a perpendicular segment,
but it's the vertical distance from the point to the line,
which is the distance between the point and its prediction.
Now, our total error is going to be the sum of
all these distances for all the points in our data set,
and sometimes we'll use this as our error.
But in this case, we'll use the average or the mean absolute error,
which is the sum of all the errors divided by M,
the number of points in our data set.
Using the sum or the average won't change
our algorithm since we would only scalar error by a constant,
namely M. And noticed something here which
is that we have an absolute value around the (y - y-hat).
The reason is that when the point is on top of the line,
the distances (y - y-hat),
but if it's under the line,
then it's (y-hat - y).
We want the error to always be positive.
Otherwise, negative errors will cancel with positive errors.
Therefore, we take the absolute value of (y - y-hat).
So, our mean absolute error is the average of all absolute errors, or in other words,
the sum of all these absolute values divided by the number of points,
which is M. We're going to plot this error over here on a graph.
Obviously as we mentioned before,
the graph has more dimensions,
but this is a two dimensional simplification of that graph.
And as we descend in this graph using gradient descent,
we get a better and better line until we find
the best possible fit with the smallest possible mean absolute error.