Now in this video, we'll learn the Mean Squared Error.
The Mean Squared Error is very similar to the Mean Absolute Error.
Again, here we have our point and our prediction.
But now, instead of taking the distance,
we're actually going to draw a square with this segment as its side.
So the area is precisely y minus y hat squared.
Notice that this is always non-negative,
so we don't need to worry about absolute values.
And our Mean squared Error is going to be the average of all these series of squares,
and we're going to have this extra factor of one-half for convenience later.
So in summary, the error is one-half times the average
of the sum of all y minus y hat square.
Again, we can take the sum and call it the Total Square Error.
But we take the average and this won't make a difference in the algorithm.
And notice, if the point is over the line or underneath the line,
the square is always going to be in a non-negative number because
the square of a real number is always going to be non-negative.
The one-half is going to be there for convenience because later,
we'll be taking the derivative of this error.
Again, we can multiply this error by any constant and
the process of minimizing it will be the exact same thing.
So this one-half does not affect anything.
So here's a pictorial representation of the error.
Here we have our points, our line,
and the error is the average of the areas of all these squares.
And here's our graph of the error.
As we descend from this mountain,
we get to the place where the error is the smallest possible and that's the same
as minimizing the average of the areas of the squares.